so in the previous quiz we have seen
that we can fetch these instructions
then we rename them to eliminate false
dependencies so let's see whether we
have any false dependencies after
renaming and what does that do to our
IPC or instructions per cycle which is
the opposite of CPI well here we had a
true dependence and that true dependence
is still there in a renamed program
similarly here we have a true dependence
and it is still there in our renamed
program and then here we have another
one and it is still there however here
we also have an output dependence from
R2 here to R2 here and then another one
to here and we have an anti- dependence
here and one here so if we look at all
of the dependencies then basically this
is a sequential program so for our
fetched program we have the cpf1 which
is is also the IPC of1 for a renamed
program however this anti- dependence is
no longer there this output dependence
is no longer there there is no anti-
dependence here and there is no output
dependence here so really here we can
execute this this and this instruction
in the first cycle and this this and
this instruction in the second cycle so
for a rename program now we have that we
can execute this this and this
instruction three instructions in the
first cycle
these three can be done in the second
cycle so overall we have six
instructions over two cycles the cycles
per instruction is two cycles for six
instructions giving us a much lower cpfs
only
0.33 or we can write it as IPC of three
meaning we execute three instructions
per cycle as you can see our renaming
gave us a much better potential for
executing this program quickly